<chapter id='&s2.idroot;quickstart'>
  <title>Quick Start Guide</title>
  <subtitle>Quick Start Guide to using S2 on LiveJournal</subtitle>

  <abstract>
    <para>
      Widely considered a myth by many users of LiveJournal.com, S2 is the
      long-awaited new style system for LiveJournal. In four years of use,
      the original LiveJournal style system has allowed LiveJournal users
      to create truly unique layouts for their journals, but shown many
      limitations due to things not considered during its initial design.
      Some functionality has been cobbled on as an afterthought, and this
      has left the style system clunky and restrictive, with some ugly
      kludges which noone really likes.
    </para>
    <para>
      S2 was conceived to remove all limitations and make LiveJournal
      truly customizable in almost any conceivable way. Redesigned from
      the ground up, S2 is completely different from the old style system,
      but introduces new functionality and makes it easier to create a
      complimentary set of journal views. It also adds new views, including
      customized comment views and, in the future, photo gallery, memory,
      and user information views.
    </para>
  </abstract>

  <section id='&s2.idroot;quickstart.intro'>
    <title>Getting to know S2</title>
    <section id='&s2.idroot;quickstart.intro.terms'>
      <title>Common Terms</title>
      <variablelist>
        <title>General Terms</title>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Journal View</term>
          <listitem>
            <simpara>
              A journal view is the name for the different parts of a
              LiveJournal account which a user can create or customize a layout for.
              Someone's journal itself is called the <quote>Recent</quote> view,
              meaning that it shows all of that user's recent entries. The most
              popular view is the <quote>Friends</quote> view, with which a user
              can read all of their <quote>friends'</quote> updates.
            </simpara>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Layers</term>
          <listitem>
            <simpara>
              S2 uses the concept of <quote>layers</quote> to provide different levels
              of customization - each layer in a style deals with a different aspect of the
              style, ranging from color to translation to HTML options and settings. A
              complete style is the result of putting its different layers together for use.
            </simpara>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <variablelist>
        <title>Style Layers</title>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Core</term>
          <listitem>
            <simpara>
              The core layer is the foundation of all styles. The core layer
              defines all of the functions and classes available to the lower
              layers. The core layer itself is fully functional as well;
              someone could use just the core definitions for each journal view
              to create a working (yet rather bland) style. The core layer is mostly
              just a base to work from, a guide to help form a complete style that
              helps by patching holes where necessary.
            </simpara>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Core - Internationalization</term>
          <listitem>
            <simpara>
              The core internationalization layer provides all of the text information
              to help display someone's journal in a different language. This layer,
              like the core layer, is only really a base or a guide to create new
              internationalization layers from.
            </simpara>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Layout</term>
          <listitem>
            <simpara>
              A layout layer is where the real customization starts. To draw a loose
              comparison to the old style system, a layout layer can be regarded as an
              S1 style except that the S2 layout covers each journal view, unlike the
              s1 style that only dealt with a single view. A layout layer, much like the core
              layer, defines its own set of properties that change the appearance and
              behavior of the layout.
            </simpara>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Internationalization</term>
          <listitem>
            <simpara>
              An internationalization layer provides all of the text information
              that pertains to a specific layout layer, so that users can select
              which language their journal should display in. A complete style uses
              text from both an internationalization layer and the core internationalization
              layer.
            </simpara>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Theme</term>
          <listitem>
            <simpara>
              A theme layer uses the color properties available in a layout layer to create
              a unique look for the style. To draw another loose comparison to the old style
              system, a theme layer is much like a color theme, except that a theme is only
              unique to one layout, unlike its S1 counterpart, which only worked for all styles.
            </simpara>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>User</term>
          <listitem>
            <simpara>
              A user layer is the final layer where most people's options will be set. Few people
              will create a user layer by hand, because a user layer is mostly handled by the customization
              wizards. To draw a final comparison to the old style system, you can think of a user
              layer as the equivalent to the <guilabel>Overrides</guilabel> box for S1, except there is
              a lot less headache involved in creating a user layer.
            </simpara>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </section>
    <!-- Explain how styles are built when requested, basically
    <section id='&s2.idroot;quickstart.intro.how'>
      <title>How it works</title>
    </section>
    -->
  </section>
  
  <section id='&s2.idroot;quickstart.use'>
    <sectioninfo>
      <authorgroup>
        <author><firstname>Melissa</firstname><surname>Della</surname></author>
        <editor><firstname>Jesse</firstname><surname>Proulx</surname></editor>
      </authorgroup>
    </sectioninfo>
    <title>Configuring your account to use S2</title>
    <para>
      To start using S2, you'll need to turn S2 on for your account. Go to
      <ulink url='&siteroot;/customize/' />, make sure the appropriate account
      is selected (if you control more than one account from the one you're
      logged into), and choose <guilabel>New System (S2)</guilabel> from the
      drop-down menu. Now save your changes (click <guibutton>Change</guibutton>).
      <tip>
        <simpara>
          You can always switch back to S1; all of your S1 styles and overrides
          are kept intact.
        </simpara>
      </tip>
    </para>
    <para>
      In this section, we'll go through the use of wizards. They are relatively
      self-explanitory by design, so this will only breifly take you through
      the steps.
    </para>
    <procedure><title>Selecting a Style</title>
      <step>
        <para>
          The first step is to choose a layout. You'll notice most of the S1 system
          styles have been ported to S2. For example purposes we'll use the default
          style, Generator. This should already be selected, if you haven't done
          any tweaking prior to reading this guide. Next to the <guibutton>Change</guibutton>
          button there is a link for layout previews. If you wish to see examples of
          other styles you may use, open this page in a new window and peruse.
        </para>
      </step>
      <step>
        <para>
          Again, for example purposes, and because we're assuming that english is your primary language,
          select <quote>English</quote> in the language section.
        </para>
      </step>
      <step>
        <para>
          Next you can choose a theme for your layout. Themes are basically just
          default sets of colors that we've chosen to help you start customizing your journal.
          You can preview each theme by selecting the <guilabel>(previews)</guilabel> link,
          located next to the <guibutton>Change</guibutton> button. If no color themes are to your liking,
          you can override any color by creating a new user layer, which we'll explain how to
          do next.
        </para>
      </step>
      <step>
        <para>
          Now that you've chosen a style, a language, and a color theme, you can
          begin creating a custom user layer by clicking the <guibutton>Customize&hellip;</guibutton>
          button at the bottom of the page.
        </para>
      </step>
    </procedure>
    <procedure><title>Creating a user layer</title>
      <step>
        <para>
          On the Customize page, the first set of options is devoted to tweaking all of the
          available colors from the style you've chosen. For brevity purposes we'll only
          change two colors (feel free to change more as you see fit).
        </para>
        <para>
          Assuming you've chosen the Generator style, scroll down to the <guilabel>Page background color
          (and around userpics)</guilabel> option and select the
          <guibutton>Override</guibutton> button; from here you can press <guibutton>Choose</guibutton>
          for a pop-up color selector, or you can simply enter the hexadecimal color code if you know it.
          For demonstration purposes you can simply type <userinput>#cef5c1</userinput> in the given box.
          Scroll down to the <guilabel>Background color for the bar below entries</guilabel> option,
          select <guibutton>Override</guibutton>, and enter the following hex code:
          <userinput>#f1fded</userinput>. If you have JavaScript enabled in your browser, you'll see the
          color previews dynamically change when you click outside of the option box.
        </para>
      </step>
      <step>
        <para>
          Now that a couple of colors have changed, scroll down to the <guilabel>Box width (pixels)</guilabel>
          option. Select <guibutton>Override</guibutton> and enter the value <literal>400</literal>.
        </para>
      </step>
      <step>
        <para>
          Move to the next section labelled <guilabel>Link text to leave a comment</guilabel>, select
          <guibutton>Override</guibutton>, and enter <literal>Post a new comment</literal>. For the next
          option, <guilabel>Link text to read comment</guilabel>, select <guibutton>Override</guibutton>
          and enter <literal>A single, lonely comment // Its a party in here with # people!</literal>.
          Enter these same values for the friends view entry comment links.
        </para>
      </step>
      <step>
        <para>
          Click on the <guibutton>Save</guibutton> button when you've completed the steps above. Now,
          view your journal. Notice th colors, the width, and the comment links.
        </para>
      </step>
    </procedure>  
  </section>

  <section id='&s2.idroot;quickstart.moreinfo'>
    <title>Where to go from here</title>
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term><xref linkend='&s2.idroot;index' /></term>
        <listitem><simpara>
          We've made a manual available that covers every topic related to using S2 on LiveJournal. As a
          matter of fact you're currently reading a chapter from the manual. To start from the beginning,
          navigate to <xref linkend='&s2.idroot;index' />.
        </simpara></listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term><ulink url='http://www.livejournal.com/community/lj_style/info'>LJ Style Discussion</ulink></term>
        <listitem><simpara>
          <ulink url='http://www.livejournal.com/community/lj_style/info'>LJ Style Discussion</ulink> is a community
          on <ulink url='http://www.livejournal.com/'>LiveJournal.com</ulink> that covers most S1 and S2 discussions.
          This community has been sanctioned by administrators of LiveJournal as an <quote>official</quote> community.
        </simpara></listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term><ulink url='http://www.livejournal.com/community/s2practice/info'>S2 Practice Discussion</ulink></term>
        <listitem><simpara>
          <ulink url='http://www.livejournal.com/community/s2practice/info'>S2 Practice Discussion</ulink> is a community
          on <ulink url='http://www.livejournal.com/'>LiveJournal.com</ulink> that deals with introducing S2 to
          members of LiveJournal's support team. The introductory text available in the community was actually used
          to write portions of this chapter.
        </simpara></listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>

</chapter>
