<chapter id="lj.intro.why_use">
  <chapterinfo>
    <title>Why Use LiveJournal?</title>
  </chapterinfo>
  <title>Why Use LiveJournal?</title>
  <para>
    LiveJournal is an open source software project, with many uses
    limited only by the imagination.  Use LiveJournal to start your
    own weblogging community, or just about any site with a community
    focus. You can use the features such as the support system and
    feedback technology, that comes bundled with LiveJournal, to run
    your own online business site.
  </para>
  <para>
    LiveJournal has many intra-office uses as well, with its easy
    update and polling features. Use LiveJournal for:
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Work journals</term>
        <listitem><para>
          Record what you're working on, or scribble notes for future reference.
        </para></listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Project logs</term>
        <listitem><para>
          Multiple members of a project team to record
          their work, post meeting minutes, and discuss ideas.
        </para></listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Announcement pages</term>
        <listitem><para>
          Recording status updates to projects or
          systems on a single page, while notifying interested users.
       </para></listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Discussion boards</term>
        <listitem><para>
          Brainstorming ideas or soliciting opinions
          with a group, in a persistent but nonintrusive medium.
        </para></listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Weblogs</term>
        <listitem><para>
          Posting links to web content of interest to a particular group.
        </para></listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </para>
  <para>
    There are many benefits of using LiveJournal
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>
        Enhances personal productivity by providing a convenient way to
        record notes in a searchable, web-accessible medium
      </para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>
        Provides visibility between departments or geographically separate offices
      </para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>
        Encourages communication by making it easy to share thoughts and comments
      </para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>
        Encourages people to get knowledge out of their heads and notebooks
        and into a visible, searchable, central location
      </para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>
        Provides more powerful tools for creating and accessing content than
        are available for ad-hoc log-structured web pages
      </para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </para>
</chapter>