<chapter id="lj.install.finishing">
  <title>Finishing Up</title>
  <para>
    You should now just about have a working LiveJournal installation. 
    There are many things you can still do, but all are outside the scope of this document.
  </para>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Configuration check</title>
    <para>
      To check that everything is setup okay, you should run the provided configuration checking tool, 
      located at <filename><envar>$LJHOME</envar>/bin/checkconfig.pl</filename>. <filename>checkconfig.pl</filename>
      will check for missing perl modules, attempt to connect to your database, and do other checks to ensure everything will work smoothly.
    </para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Start things up</title>
    <para>If you haven't restarted Apache, you'll want to do that now:</para>

<screen><prompt>#</prompt> <userinput>apachectl stop</userinput>
<prompt>#</prompt> <userinput>apachectl start</userinput></screen>
    
    <para>Note that doing a "graceful" or "restart" is not guaranteed to work.  The LiveJournal code
      doesn't implement any mod_perl restart handlers, and weird things have been reported to happen
      using <userinput>apachectl restart</userinput>.
    </para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>The system user</title>
    <para>
      To administrate your site properly, you will need to create the system user that'll have
      privileges to give privileges to other users:
    </para>

<screen><prompt>$</prompt> <userinput>$LJHOME/bin/upgrading/make_system.pl</userinput></screen>

    <para>It'll prompt you for the password to use for the system account and then sets it all up.</para>
    <para>You now have the ability to login to your LJ site as user <quote>system</quote> with the password
      you set and then grant priviledges from the admin section to other users:
    </para>
    <para>http://your-lj-server/admin/priv/</para>
  </formalpara>
  <para>
    If you have any questions, join the <ulink url="http://www.livejournal.com/users/lj_everywhere/info">"lj_everywhere"</ulink>
    community on LiveJournal.com and post your questions.  We'd love to help you out.
  </para>
</chapter>
<!--
Local Variables:
mode:sgml
sgml-parent-document: ("index.xml" "part" "chapter")
End:
-->
